<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal Stuffs on Budiman JOJO</title>
    <link>https://budimanjojo.com/categories/terminal-stuffs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terminal Stuffs on Budiman JOJO</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 23:54:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://budimanjojo.com/categories/terminal-stuffs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing Dotfiles with chezmoi</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/12/13/managing-dotfiles-with-chezmoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 23:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/12/13/managing-dotfiles-with-chezmoi/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The biggest difference between my setup and your setup might be our configuration files. In Unix world we call them dotfiles. Dotfiles are just files whose filename starts with a dot and will be hidden by default in our file managers.
Usually we have several machines that we use consequently, and we want all those machines to share the same environment. And that’s why most most people will have have own collection of dotfiles stored somewhere so they can easily migrate them over to their new machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Media Server Series #2 &amp;#8211; Secure SSH</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2019/11/30/raspberry-pi-media-server-series-2-secure-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 10:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2019/11/30/raspberry-pi-media-server-series-2-secure-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the second part of my Raspberry Pi Media Server series. On previous post, I wrote about installing Manjaro Linux ARM into my Raspberry Pi 4. Now, we are going to secure our SSH server on Raspberry Pi so that we can at least prevent brute-force attempt on our future home media server from the evil outside world. Securing SSH server is one of the most crucial part of every server that can be accessible on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
