<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Budiman JOJO</title>
    <link>https://budimanjojo.com/categories/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Budiman JOJO</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 17:37:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://budimanjojo.com/categories/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I GitOps Home Assistant Configurations</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/11/04/gitops-home-assistant-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 17:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/11/04/gitops-home-assistant-configurations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I always love the idea of GitOps, where everything I have in a git repo represents the current state of my application. But not everything are made for GitOps, so we have to sort of “make it work”. In this post, I will show you how I manage to GitOps my Home Assistant configurations. Spoiler, this is hacky and messy at the same time, so please bear this in mind before continuing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Kubernetes Nodes Reboot with Kured</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/28/kured-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 16:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/28/kured-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Having an up-to-date Kubernetes node is important, especially security updates. Sometimes an update requires a reboot to take effect, and you don’t want to keep checking them manually. In this post, I will share about how I automate my Kubernetes nodes to reboot when necessary using Kured.
Linux Distro Specific Before doing the actual setting up process, every Linux distribution has its own way to decide whether a reboot is required or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Substitution in Flux GitOps</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/27/variable-substitution-in-flux-gitops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/27/variable-substitution-in-flux-gitops/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Sometimes there are values that you want to use multiple times in your manifest files. Usually, we define them using a config map or secret and we either mount them as a file or environment variable. This is easy if you don’t use GitOps and you only have a small amount of pods. Also, having a single configmap and secret will clean up a lot of mess out of your cluster, and this is what variable substitution will do for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux Secret Management with SOPS age</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/23/flux-secret-management-with-sops-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 16:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/23/flux-secret-management-with-sops-age/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Following my previous post about Kubernetes management using Flux, this post will cover secret management using SOPS and age. SOPS is a tool to encrypt and decrypt text files while age is the encryption tool that is simple, modern, and secure.
Reasons to Use SOPS and age Flux supports Sealed Secrets and SOPS as secret management, but I prefer SOPS for multiple reasons. You may or may not agree with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Manage My Kubernetes Manifests Using Flux</title>
      <link>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/20/how-i-manage-my-kubernetes-manifests-using-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 18:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budimanjojo.com/2021/10/20/how-i-manage-my-kubernetes-manifests-using-flux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitOps is currently the most popular way to manage your services. It’s sort of what DevOps is but with Git. To put it in a simple way, it is a practice where you manage everything through git. Whatever you have in your git repository is what your cluster current state is. Because GitOps is so popular there are a lot of new tools focusing on GitOps right now, and Flux is one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
